Guide to the New-York Historical Society Poster Collection [dates] PR 55
New-York Historical Society
- Series IX. Other Subjects, 18xx-20xx
  - Subseries IX.A. Chronological, 18xx-20xx
    - "Official Summary of Electoral Votes cast for each President of the United States of America.", 1911 (Folder 09-03)
      The chart of electoral votes from 1789-1908 was compiled by the Clerk of the U.S. House of Representatives. Also explains how electors are chosen and how many will be apportioned to each state in 1913.
    - "Instruction to Voters" (New York City Board of Elections), 1905 (Folder 09-03)
      Printed by Martin B. Brown, Co. Printers. The poster sets out 7 rules and Chapter 693, An Act to Amend the Penal Code. The Commissioners of the Board of Elections are John R. Voorhis, Charles B. Page, John Maguire, and Michael J. Dady.
    - Independence League Watcher's Tally Card, 1906 (Folder 09-03)
      Watcher's Tally Card for New York Election held November 6, 1906. On back, there is a grid with Parties going across the top and the elected positions down the side. There are tally marks filling in the grid. Acquisition date (?) on front: Dec. 2, 1932.
    - "Department of Health", 1907 (Folder 09-03)
      On the back, there are excerpts from a letter from Dr. Sydney Carney, Jr. dated July 3, 1907. The letter explains that Dr. Thomas Darlington (the donor of the poster) told Dr. Carney that these signs were fastened over the street sweeping carts in New York City after the Board of Health took charge of removing garbage from the streets when the street cleaning drivers went on strike. Acquisition date: Dec. 23, 1910.
    - "Meeting of Teachers" on the subject of "Teachers' Bill", 1907 May 22 (Folder 09-03)
      Printed by Press of Kiesling Brothers. Taxpayers were also invited to the meeting held at Morris High School at 166th Street & Boston Road. On back, in pencil, "E.B. Child/39".
    - Third Annual Outing of the Jackson Democratic Club of the 34th District, 1909 (Folder 09-03)
      Printed by The Kiesling Company. A picture of Arthur H. Murphy, Executive Member of the Board of Directors, is featured on the poster. The poster also lists the Officers, the Board of Directors and the members of the Reception Committee, the Outing Committee, and the Games Committee. The outing was held on August 16, 1909, at Witzel's Point View Grove. On front, in pencil, "E.B. Child/39".
    - The Republican Club / 35th Assembly District Outing and Games Day, 1909 (Folder 09-03)
      Thomas W. Whittle, Chairman of the Board of Governors of The Republic Club/35th Assembly District, is pictured on the poster. The rest of the Officers and Board of Governors are listed as are the names of all on the Committee of Arrangements. The Games were held on Sept. 11, 1909, at M.J. Kane's Clason Point View-on-the-Sound. On the front, in pencil, "E.B. Child/39".
    - Bronx Church House (171st Street and Fulton Avenue) The Night of Nights - Basket Ball and Dance, [1910s] (Folder 09-02)
      Poster printed by Henry Emmerson. Night included two basketball games and a dance. On back, in pencil, "E.B. Child/39".
    - Board of Education, City of New York presentation poster of the Independence Day Committee, 1915 (Folder 09-03)
      Depicts a series of vignettes of important events in American history, including the end of the Civil War and the building of the Panama Canal. Stamped on back, "The Henry A. Ogden Collection of the New York Historical Society. October 20, 1936".
    - "Instructions to Voters" (New York City Board of Elections), 1915 (Folder 09-03)
      Printed by M.B. Brown Printing & Binding Co. The instructions include 3 steps and Article 74 of the Penal Code is set out below the instructions. The Commissioners of the Board of Elections are Edward F. Boyle, Moses M. McKee, James Kane, and Jacob A. Livingston. Acquisition date (?) on front: Dec. 2, 1932 and "Child".
    - "Instructions to Voters" (New York City Board of Elections), 1916 (Folder 09-03)
      Poster printed by M.B. Brown Printing & Binding Co. The poster sets out 5 steps of instructions and an amended version of Article 74 of the Penal Code. The Commissioners of the Board of Elections are Edward F. Boyle, Moses M. McKee, James Kane, and Jocaob A. Livingston. Acquisition date (?) on front: Dec 1, 19_2.
    - "Instructions to Voters" (New York City Board of Elections), 1917 (Folder 09-03)
      Printed by M.B. Brown Printing & Binding Co. The instructions set out 3 steps for voting and Article 74 of the Penal Code. The Commissioners of the Board of Elections are Edward F. Boyle, Moses M. McKee, James Kane, and Jacob A. Livingston.
    - Federal Registration for Election District 17, Assembly District 35, 1917 (Folder 09-03)
      Federal registration dated June 5, 1917. "Register Here".
    - The Mayflower Compact, 1920 (Folder 09-01)
      Printed by Tiffany & Co. in 1920 on the three hundredth anniversary of the signing of "The Compact". On back, in pencil, "Presented by Frank B. Porter November 30, 1920."
    - Advertisement of The Pennsylvania Academy of Fine Arts Summer School in Chester Springs, Chester County, Pennsylvania., [1920s] (Folder 09-04)
      The poster features photographs of the studio classes and grounds at the summer school. Board, lodging and tuition was $15 per week.
    - Sweet Land of Liberty, Of Thee I Sing, 1921 (Folder 09-01)
      Removed from folder for an exhibition on 1/18/2020. Poster was designed by Wallace Robinson and printed by John J. Cusick.
    - Red Cross Advertisement, 1921 (Folder 09-02)
      Poster design features a red cross superimposed over 1921. Aquisition date (?) on back: Oct. 1, 1947.
    - Advertisement for Woman's Home Companion for July featuring best photograph of Mrs. Roosevelt., 1921 (Folder 09-05)
      Poster printed by The Crowell Publishing Company. Photograph of Mrs. Roosevelt copyrighted in 1903 by George Prince. Acquisition date (?) on front: June 4, 1921.
    - The (Warren G.) Harding Memorial, 1923 (Folder 09-01)
      The poster gives dates for the memorial from December 9th through the 16th of 1923 and states, "subscription memberships received here". The poster was designed by Dan Smith after photo by Edmonston.
    - "The Government would be grateful if you would -- Shop Early, Wrap Carefully, Address Plainly and Mail Promptly" (Postmaster General poster), 1923-1929 (Folder 09-02)
      Printed by the Government Printing Office. On top, labelled as "N.Y. Poster 10-C". Harry S. New is the Postmaster General on the poster. He served from 1923-1929. On back, in pencil, is "EB Child/39".
    - Appeal by the New York Public Library Staff Association., 1924 (Folder 09-01)
      The appeal is asking the public to lobby the Board of Estimate to keep the public libraries up to standard with increased salaries to the trained staff and increases in the volumes of books. Poster designed by R. Ferryman.
    - Huguenot-Walloon Tercentenary Settlement of New Netherland Celebration Proclamation of New York State, 1924 (Folder 09-04)
      The Proclamation by Alfred E. Smith, Governor of New York, designated the month of May 1924 for the observance of the Tercentenary of the Founding of New Netherland. A note at the bottom states that the U.S. Government has issued a commemorative half dollar coin on sale for $1.00. Aquisition date (?) on back: March 17, 1924.
    - La Morte Di Wilson in La Nazione della Sera [Italian], 1924 (Folder 09-04)
      Newspaper supplement to the Feruary 4, 1924 edition of La Nazione della Sera. Pagine 6.
    - Announcement of Albany's Tercentenary 3 Day Historical Pageant., 1924 (Folder 09-04)
      Poster printed by J.B. Lyon Company Printers, Albany. Celebration took place from June 1-3, 1924. Aquisition date (?) on front: June 11, 1924.
    - "United States of America First Defense Test Day", 1924 (Folder 09-04)
      Poster was lithographed by 1st Lt. David Klein, O.R.C., 42 Ross St., Brooklyn, N.Y. The first "Defense Test" day was scheduled for September 12, 1924.
    - "Fete de la Tour Eiffel", 1924 (Folder 09-05)
      Poster printed by Les Nouvelles Affiches Cappiello - Atelier D'Art Devambez. Designed by "L. Cappiello. 1924" Sponsored by the U.S. and French presidents with profits to benefit the High Altitude Sanatorium Villages of France and Franco-American social services. Acquisition date (?) on back: Dec. 31, 1953.
    - "National Picture Week". American Art Bureau., [1925] (Folder 09-01)
      2 copies. Slightly different formats.
    - "Pictures are Magic Windows". American Art Bureau., undated (Folder 09-01)
      Poster designed by Lawson Fenerty. Includes A.A.B.'s slogan, "Beautify with Pictures".
    - Fundraising Appeal to complete the Cathedral of St. John the Divine., [1925] (Folder 09-01)
      2 copies. The poster is designed by Adolf Treidler and published by Carey & Sons, N.Y. On back of both copies, in pencil, acquisition date (?) Feb. 28, 1925.
    - B.M.T. Travelguide featuring Whitehall Street Station, 1925 (Folder 09-04)
      Poster printed by Allied Printing. Advertising for the B.M.T. subway lines. Poster includes a photograph of Fraunces Tavern -- one of the important sites near the Whitehall Street Station. On front, in pencil, "Gift of Mr. Hevlyn D. Benson. Dec. 6, 1935".
    - Safety appeal by the Broadway Merchants Association of Brooklyn, Inc. [BMA]., 1926 (Folder 09-01)
      "Save Your Life! Cross At The Crosswalks". Written note on front, "Originated by Hevlyn D. Benson for the B-M-A Safety Drive 1926." On front and on back, in pencil, "Gift of H.D. Benson Dec. 12, 1935".
    - "Sesqui-Centennial Celebration, July 9, 1926" (Provincial Congress of New York's adoption of the Declaration of Independence) (Folder 09-01)
      The celebration is under the auspices of the New York State Department of Education and The Westchester County Historical Society. The poster is printed by The Knapp Co., Inc. of New York. Stamped on back, "The Henry A. Ogden Collection of The New York Historical Society October 20, 1936".
    - Congregation Kehilath Israel Announcement of New Location for the High Holidays, [1926] (Folder 09-02)
      The congregation relocated from 1162 Jackson Avenue to Crotona Park and Suburban Place into a synagogue designed by Emery Roth. On back, in pencil, "E.B. Child/39".
    - "Book Week", 1927 (Folder 09-01)
      Book Week ran from November 13th to 19th.
    - The Salvation Army. Maintenance Appeal, 1927 (Folder 09-01)
      Appeal for greater New York area. Signed by artist, G. Cary (?).
    - "Lindbergh Flies Alone", [1927?] (Folder 09-04)
      Poster printed by P.J. Carey & Sons, N.Y. Reprinted editorial from The Sun, May 21, 1927. Aquisiton date (?) on back: "O.T. Barck, Sr. July 8, 1954."
    - Lecture Series for St. John's the Evangelist Church, [1928] (Folder 09-01)
      The lecture series included two Sunday evening lectures: one by Will Irwin on Herbert Hoover, A Personality, and one by Sen. Royal S. Copeland on Gov. Alfred E. Smith and The Purpose of Government. On the back, there is some further information about St. John's the Evangelist Church. There is also, in pen, "Gift of Mr. E.B. Child. Feb. 16, 1933".
    - 1928 Presidential Campaign Informational Poster (Folder 09-04)
      Poster is copyrighted by The Osborne Company, Newark, New Jersey. The poster advertises the Weber-Bunke-Lange Coal Co. on West 96th Street in New York City. Poster includes photographs of all the U.S. Presidents up to Calvin Coolidge, photographs of the presidential and vice presidential candidates of 1928, and photographs of the White House, Oval Office, and Capitol. The poster also lists the current Senate, The Electoral and the Popular Vote for President, By Parties and States, 1920-1924, and several facts about the Presidency, including salary and minimum age.
    - Haym Salomon Monument Committee., 1929 (Folder 09-01)
      Poster seeking donations to erect monument of Haym Salomon, Revolutionary Patriot. The Committee is under the auspices of the Federation of Polish Jews in America. Poster designed by Mitchell Loeb. On back, in pencil, "O.T. Barck, Sr. July 8, 1954".
    - Van Cortlandt House Museum, undated (Folder 09-01)
      Admission times and the further information that admission was free except on Thursdays when a 25 cent fee covered afternoon tea in the Colonial Kitchen. Poster signed by F.L.V.H.
    - The Art Directors Club of New York's first Dinner Meeting of the Season informational poster, 1930 (Folder 09-02)
      Russel Crouse was scheduled to speak on his recently published book, "Mr. Currier and Mr. Ives" at the Hotel Martinique on Friday, Dec. 19, 1930. "Engravings by Knapp. Typography by Schmidt & Lepiz. Printing contributed by Kenilworth Press." On back, in pen, "Gift of Eugenia Maurer Fuerstenberg (daughter of Louis Maurer) June 30, 1939".
    - The United States Army Recruiting Service Recruitment Poster, 1931 (Folder 09-02)
      Poster features portrait of George Washington on a horse with the words: "First in War, First in Peace, First the Hearts of His Countrymen -". Aquisition date (?) on back: Feb. 17, 1932.
    - Washington Headquarters, Morristown, N.J., Washington Bi-Centennial Celebration, 1932 (Folder 09-02)
      Celebration scheduled for July 4-5th at the Washington Headquarters in Morristown.
    - Unemployed Council of Greater New York Grand Parade and Mass Meeting against the "Block-Aid System", 1932 (Folder 09-02)
      H. Benjamin, National Secretary of Unemployed Councils, U.S.A., and Carl Winter, Secretary of Greater New York Council, were to speak at the parade and meeting to urge workers to unite and demand cash relief and unemployment insurance. On front, in pencil, "Gift of Mr. E.B. Child. May 23, 1934".
    - The International Labor Defense Demonstration Against War and Fascism., 1934 (Folder 09-02)
      March held on Aug. 4, 1934 from Columbus Circle to Madison Square. "Join our ranks (International Labor Defense)... to learn the Truth about Strikes and Labor Struggles." On back, in pencil, "July 28, 1934".
    - "Scenes from the Living Theatre - No. 1 Masses and Men", 1934 (Folder 09-02)
      Montage of photos by Film Photo League. Photos of poverty and protests on social and economic issues. On back, in pencil, "Communist Movement, N.Y. Spring 1934"
    - The American Museum of Natural History Lecture Series for Members, 1935 (Folder 09-05)
      Lectures included one on the new planetarium and one on the Conquest of Everest.
    - The American Museum of Natural History Lecture Series for Children of Members, 1935 (Folder 09-05)
      Children's lectures included Exploring under the Sea and Arctic Adventures.
    - "Save Lives Through Safe Habits. Works Progress Administration", 1936 (Folder 09-05)
      Poster designed by I.L.S. On front, in pencil, "W.P.A. Placard on public school building, 132 W. 55th St." On back, in pencil, "Gift of Mrs. George Wilde. Nov. 19, 1936".
    - F.B.I. $10,000 Reward Post about kidnapping and murder of Charles Fletcher Mattson of Tacoma, Washington., 1937 (Folder 09-05)
      Kidnapping occurred on December 27, 1936 and reward for information posted on January 12, 1937 by John Edgar Hoover, Director of the F.B.I. Acquisition date (?) on back: May 7, 1946.
    - Advertisement for "The Village Fair. Washington Mews, Just South of No. 1 Fifth Ave.", 1938 (Folder 09-05)
      Poster drawn by Hirschfeld. The Fair was held to benefit the Spanish Children's Milk Fund, Auspices Women's Division Medical Bureau, and the North American Committee to Aid Spanish Democracy. On back, in pencil, "Gift of H.B. Hoffman. July 15, 1938."
    - Printing & Allied Industries 5th Educational Graphic Arts Exposition, 1939 (Folder 09-05)
      Poster designed by Goring. Exposition held at the Grand Central Palace. There are also stamps with the same graphics. Acquisition date (?) on back: Aug. 4, 1939.
    - "Ernest Dudley Chase Pictorial Maps Price $1.00 each" Advertisement, 1939 (Folder 09-05)
      Poster copyrighted by Ernest Dudley Chase, Boston, Massachusetts. Along with the poster is a smaller pamphlet with a further description of the pictorial maps which include maps of France, Germany, Spain and Portugal, British Isles, Boston, Manhattan, and the United States, among others. Poster was folded and sent to the New-York Historical Society, postmarked 1939 from Boston. Sent by "Beautiful Pictorial Maps by Ernest Dudley Chase".
    - New York City W.P.A. Historical Records Survey Informational Sessions, [1940] (Folder 09-02)
      "This work pays your community" "Is doing for your community ... Guide to depositories manuscript collections...Old town record transcriptions...American Imprints Inventory...Inventory of the church archives in New York City...Inventory of City County and Borough archives of New York City". 2 copies. On back, in pencil, on both copies, "May 31, 1940".
    - "Printing Bulwark of Liberty 1440-1940" (Folder 09-05)
      Poster printed by the International Association of Printing House Craftsmen to celebrate the 500th anniversary of the Invention of Printing. Acquisition date (?) on back: Oct. 21, 1940.
    - "Printing Ink Makes People Think. 500th Anniversary of the Invention of Printing, 1940." (Folder 09-05)
      Poster printed by the International Association of Printing House Craftsmen in cooperation with the National Association of Printing Ink Makers. Acquisition date (?) on back: Oct. 21, 1940.
    - "500th Anniversary of the Invention of Printing 1440-1940. Signalizing the Service of Printing to the Community" (Folder 09-05)
      Poster printed by the Interantional Association of Printing House Craftsmen. Acquisition date (?) on back: Oct. 21, 1940.
    - The Cuneo Press, Inc. Display Sheet at the 1940 World's Fair in New York (Folder 09-05)
      The Display Sheet is a "page from the Sermon on the Mount...set in the reconstructed Donat type, the first known movable type (1440), and...printed on a replica of the Gutenberg press exhibited by The Cuneo Press, Inc. in celebration of 500 years of printing at the World's Fair of 1940 in New York." Acquisition date (?) on back: Oct. 14, 1941.
    - Advertisement for The Old Fort Niagara, c. 1940 (Folder 09-02)
      The advertisement which included a space for folders to takeaway, was copyrighted by Old Fort Niagara Association, Inc. and executed by N.Y. State Art Project W.P.A.. On front, in pencil, 1940. Aquisition date (?) on back: July 2, 1940.
    - "Unification - June 12, 1940" (I.R.T. and Mayor of New York City) (Folder 09-05)
      The Interborough Rapid Transit Company's The Elevated Express Vol. XII, No. 22. Printed by The Ma(...)hbanks Press, New York. Designed by Fred Cooper. Acquisition date (?) on back: June 13, 1940.
    - The Artists Guild Moonlight Sail, 1940 (Folder 09-05)
      The Moonlight Sail was on Wednesday, July 17th, on the palatial river steamer, S.S. Mayflower, leaving from the foot of Battery Place. Stamped date of Nov 3 1944 on front. Note on back, in pencil, "Recv July 9/40" and stamped, "Please Post".
    - "It's Here! It's Great!! It's the Real Thing!!! which means Super-entertainment!!" (Committee for Peace), 1940 (Folder 09-05)
      The event was on Oct. 5, 1940 at 79 E. 10th St. and Woody on guitar was part of the entertainment. Acquisition date (?) on back: Nov. 4, 1941.
    - "Use Water Wisely!!!" (Department of Water Supply, Gas and Electricity)., 1941 (Folder 09-05)
      New York City reservoirs only 1/3 filled because of drought. LaGuardia was Mayor and Patrick Quilty was Commissioner of the Department of Water Supply. Acquisition date (?) on back: Dec. 16, 1941.
    - The Nordacs Club, Inc. 23rd Annual Gala All Star Show and Dance., 1941 (Folder 09-05)
      Poster printed by Allied Printers of New York and approved by Theater Authority, Inc. The Show and Dance was for the benefit of the Welfare Fund and held at the Manhattan Center with music by Sammy Wilson & his orchestra. Acquisition date (?) on back: Nov. 4, 1941.
    - "Stop Needless Noise. Help America Keep Calm" (Police Department City of New York, Safety Program), [1942] (Folder 09-02)
      2 copies. Poster designed by Howard Scott. Contribution by National Noise Abatement Council and F.H. La Guardia, Mayor.
    - "Book Week", 1942 (Folder 09-05)
      "Forward with Books" slogan. November 15th-21st. Acquisition date (?) on back: Nov. 9, 1942.
    - "These are the Times ...." December 1942. (Oscar Hayman Fabrics of Fashionation) (Folder 09-05)
      Poster printed by Alvin Gardner Co., advertising. Features portrait of and quote by Thomas Paine. Also quote by Oscar Hayman referencing "turning point of a great war." Acquisition date (?) on back: Dec. 16, 1942.
    - Sociedades Hispanas Confederadas conmemora el 19 de Julio, 1943 (Folder 09-02)
      The commemoration of Spanish heriocs and sacrifice was held at The Manhattan Center on 34th Street. Noted at the bottom was the radio station to hear the Voice of Sociedades Hispanas Confederadas every day but Sundays from 9:30 -10:00 p.m. Aquisition date (?) on back: Sept. 12, 1944.
    - Supplement to Woman's Day Magazine's Christmas issue of 1945 (Folder 09-05)
      "Reprinted from Woman's Day, The A&P Magazine. Copyright, 1946, by Stores Publishing Company, Inc." Attached note from Woman's Day magazine explains that Olin Downes, authority on music, chose masterpieces of grand opera from which the most remembered scenes have been drawn by John Held, Jr. The chart was reproduced from the Woman's Day Christmas issue. Acquisition date (?) on back: Dec. 5, 1945.
    - Noche Atomica Grand Ball with 2 Orchestras -- Marcelino Guerra with Ayala on piano and Montesino and his rhythm set, 1946 (Folder 09-05)
      Poster printed by Manhattan Press. The grand ball took place on Saturday, January 26th, at the Hunt's Point Palace. On back, in pencil, "Feb. 1, 1946. Gift of Henry B. Hoffmann."
    - Income Tax Return Filing Reminder, 1946 (Folder 09-05)
      Poster printed by the U.S. Government Printing Office. Reminder that if income was $500 or more, need to file tax return with District Collector of Internal Revenue by March 15th. Acquisition date (?) on back: April 30, 1946.
    - Supplement to Woman's Day Magazine's April issue of 1946 (Folder 09-05)
      "Reprinted from Woman's Day, The A&P Magazine. Copyright, 1946, by Stores Publishing Company, Inc." Attached note from Woman's Day Magazine explains that the chart depicts paintings of great masters compiled by Thomas Craven and laid-out by George Salter. Reproduced from the April issue. Acquisition date (?) on back: April 1, 1946.
    - Pennsylvania Railroad Strike Warning Poster, [1946] (Folder 09-02)
      Alert that the railworkers were scheduled to strike at 4:00 p.m. on Saturday, May 18th.
    - Philipse Castle Restoration 3rd Birthday Celebration (Sleepy Hollow), 1946 (Folder 09-02)
      Celebration took place on July 4, 1946. Included a restored Headless Horseman Bridge and advertised as Greater New York's most amazing garden spot. Aquisition date (?) on back: June 14, 1946.
    - Advertisement for U.S. Savings Bonds, 1946 (Folder 09-05)
      Poster printed by the Government Printing Office. "Official U.S. Treasury Poster SBD 77A". Aquisition date (?) on back: June 17, 1946.
    - "Happy Birthday Pennsy. One hundred years of Transportation Progress." (Pennsylvania Railroad & New York City Transit System), 1946 (Folder 09-05)
      The Subway Sun, Vol. XIII, No. 9. Designed by OPPY. Acquisition date (?) on back: May 31, 1946.
    - U.S. Frigate Constitution (Old Ironsides) 150 Birthday Celebration, 1947 (Folder 09-02)
      Poster was printed by Patrick J. Connelly, Postmaster of Boston 9, Massachusetts. The celebration exercises were conducted by Robert E. Hannegan, Postmaster General, and included the introduction of a commemorative stamp. Aquisition date (?) on back: Nov. 13, 1947.